Karen D. Reisdorf 2907 Timber Ridge Drive Mt. Airy, MD 21771 (410) 207-1050

OBJECTIVE

Challenging academic position in which a passion for education and strong organizational skills combined with excellent communication and interpersonal skills will be fully utilized.

CAREER SUMMARY

Seasoned educator with experience in teaching middle school through college Mathematics. Developed daily class schedule for Kindergarten through 8th grade parochial school, and grades 6-12 in present position, integrating extracurricular classes within the academic structure. Experience with curriculum mapping within the Mathematics curriculum, grades 9-12. Actively participated in three Middles States evaluations and strategic plans. Provided private tutoring for students at all levels for 30 years. Experienced assessor for the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards. Previous Adjunct Math Lab Instructor at community college level.

CLASSROOM EXPERIENCE

Maryvale Preparatory School 2006- present

High School Math Teacher- 7 years

Dean of Junior Advisory

St. John School, Westminster, MD 1989-2006

Middle School Math Teacher- 7 years

1st Grade Teacher- 10 years

Carroll Community College, Westminster, MD 2002-2005

Adjunct Math Lab Instructor

St. Irene School, Warrenville, IL 1986-1987 (Middle School Math Teacher)

St. Luke School, Indianapolis, IN 1977-1978 (Middle School Math Teacher)

Eisenhower High School, New Berlin, WI 1976-1977 (High School Math Teacher)

Indian Trail Junior High School, Addison, IL 1975-1976 (Middle School Math Teacher)

PROFESSIONAL

National Board for Professional Teaching Standards Assessor

NCEA Member

NSA Mathematics Workshop- \$2500 grant recipient

Target Scholarship recipient

Teacher Representative on School Board and PTF Board, St. John School

Parent Club President and Board Member, St. John's at Prospect Hall

St. Elizabeth Ann Seton Catholic School Teacher of the Year Award 2004

Cardinal's Award for Teaching Excellence 2005

EDUCATION

Coppin State College, Baltimore, MD

Masters in Education 2003 Summa Cum Laude

University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA

B.S. in Math-Secondary Education 1975 Magna Cum Laude